healthnet.com 2002-06-11

# Health Net | Privacy

|  |     
---|---  
  
Health Net, Incorporated, Health Net of California, Inc, and all affiliated companies are committed to maintaining the privacy of those who communicate to us on our web site. Any information which is voluntarily provided to Health Net through this web site is kept confidential and protected and is treated with the same consideration and confidentiality as any information sent to us by the US mail or communicated to us by telephone. 

**Security**

Our web site requires users to give us unique identifiers in order to log into many areas of the site. These identifiers include, as appropriate, the subscriber identification number (usually the social security number), provider identification number, employer identification number, and/or assigned personal identification number (PIN). These unique identifiers are collected to verify the user's identity and eligibility, in order to protect our members from the release of sensitive or personally identifiable information to unauthorized users. 

Health Net urges all Internet users to take responsible and appropriate steps to safeguard their identification numbers to help protect their privacy. 

This site has additional security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control, including but not limited to: 

  * Built-in firewalls (a combination of computer hardware and software) to keep unauthorized users from accessing information through Health Net's computer network. 
  * Encryption technology, including Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). 

**Outside Vendors and Contractors**

We have hired outside vendors and contractors to assist us with the development, improvement and maintenance of this site. We have taken measures to ensure that any personally identifiable information given to us remains with Health Net, and is not passed through to the outside vendor or contractor, unless the user voluntarily gives the vendor that information. Please note, this site contains links to other sites. Health Net is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other web sites. 

**Information Gathering**

Health Net will not collect nonpublic personal information about you, unless you provide us that information voluntarily. If you provide personal information to us voluntarily through our web site, we will not sell, license or transmit that information outside Health Net, and those affiliated companies involved in administering or providing services for our health benefits plans, or unless we do so in accordance with express authorization you have given us. We will disclose information in compliance with applicable laws and regulations and will require the recipient to protect the information and use it only for the purpose provided.

Nonpublic personal information means data unique to the individual, such as a name, address, social security number or telephone number. Health Net may collect nonpublic personal information about you from you or your representative on application forms, through requests for information or services, or in order to deliver requested materials to you, respond to your questions, or deliver a product or service.

Health Net routinely gathers quantitative information on web site activity, including the number of users to the site, and the pages visited. No personally identifiable information is collected in this routine activity. Our site also uses order forms for users to request information, products, and services. Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and information about our company to our users. The user's contact information is also used to get in touch with the user when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. We also use user Internet Protocol address information to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our web site, and we use cookies* to deliver content specific to your interests. 

**Choice/Opt-Out/Correct/Update**

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and/or our partners at the point where we request information about the user. This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided, removing their information from our database in order to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service: 

  * You can send e-mail to [webteam@healthnet.com](mailto:webteam@healthnet.com)
  * You can visit the following URL: http://www2.healthnet.com/general/contact_us/
  * You can send mail to the following postal address: 

_21281 Burbank Boulevard, Woodland Hills, CA 91367_

  * You can call the following telephone number: (800) 342-2737 

**Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this web site, you can contact 

Web Team   
Health Net   
21281 Burbank Boulevard  
Woodland Hills   
CA 91367   
webteam@healthnet.com 

*Cookies are pieces of information that a web site transfers to a user's hard disk for purposes of record keeping. Cookies can be beneficial by storing information about a user's preferences. Many major web sites use cookies as a standard practice to provide useful features. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. A user can set his or her browser to refuse cookies, but he or she may not be able to take full advantage of a web site.
